motleyhealth.com 2019-11-19

# Privacy, GDPR and Cookies Notice - MotleyHealth®

Motley Health respects the privacy and confidentiality of personal data submitted to the site by our visitors. We will not share any personal information submitted to our website.

The web site owners undertake to honor or exceed the legal requirements of medical/health information privacy that apply in the country and state where the web site is located.

Everyone can read all articles and comments on this site and make personal use of this information. No information may be republished without our written authorisation.

## Community Comments

What information do we collect? If you leave a comment your name (comment name), email address and IP address will be kept on the database. This is standard operating procedure for any blog or forum. If you wish your comment/s to be deleted for any reason your private information will also be removed from out database. You may of course use a pseudonym (false name) and email address for comments if you are concerned about privacy. We do not collect email addresses for the purpose of comment update notifications – this has been disabled following the GDPR update. If you wish to know if there has been a reply to your comment, check back on a regular basis.

Your email address will never be shared, and it will only be used by us if you subscribe to comment updates. If you raise a delicate question in the forums/comments part of the site we may contact you directly rather than publish the discussion publicly. Nobody outside of MotleyHealth has access to the private data stored on the servers.

## Email Subscription

If you subscribe to the blog, it will be managed by [Google’s Feedburner service](https://feeds.feedburner.com/Motleyhealth), which is a double opt-in email subscription service. They have their own cookie / privacy policy that you can read here: [https://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/privacy.](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  

## GDPR and Your Cookies

The UK Government and EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) have passed new legislation with regards to the use of cookies. The following section explains which Cookies MotleyHealth.com uses and why we use them.

We only use third party products, such as Google Analytics and Google AdWords, which may collect and track your data. No personally identifiable data is collected.

MotleyHealth.com uses Persistant Cookies for website analytics and performance

  * Google Analytics: We use this tool to improve our website for the benefit of our users and make site improvements, all data collected is anonymous. For more information on Google Analytics cookie usage, please visit their website- [http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)
  * YouTube: A cookie is only stored on your browser if you a play an embedded video on our website. Don’t click play on any of our videos if you don’t want to have a YouTube cookie set. YouTube is owned by Google and their privacy policy can be found here –  [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

## Google and the DoubleClick DART cookie

Some of the adverts displayed on our site are provided by Google, and use cookies to target advertising. Please be aware that:

  * Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads based on your visit to this site and other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, the visit [Network Advertising Initiative.](https://www.networkadvertising.org/)

## WordPress.org Cookies

WordPress.org websites also collect cookies for users who post comment. As MotleyHealth.com is built using WordPress, these cookies apply to our users.

When visitors comment on the any of our articles or blogs, they will have cookies stored on their computer. This is purely for convenience, so that the visitor will not be required to re-type all their information again when they want to leave another comment on our site in the future.

**Three cookies are set for WordPress commentators:**  comment_author, comment_author_email, comment_author_url

The commenter cookies are set to expire a little less than one year from the time they are set.

## Prohibiting the collection of Cookies

If you would like to prevent MotleyHealth.com from collecting cookies when you visit our site, please update the privacy setting in your chosen web browser. You can directly control cookie acceptance from there:

Google: [https://myaccount.google.com/privacy?pli=1](https://accounts.google.com/ServiceLogin?passive=1209600&osid=1&continue=https://myaccount.google.com/general-light&followup=https://myaccount.google.com/general-light&csig=AF-SEnaQlH2eKs9Gi1Ns:1555592121)

Mozilla Firefox: [http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/privacy/](https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/privacy/)

Internet Explorer: [http://windows.microsoft.com/en-gb/windows7/how-to-manage-cookies-in-internet-explorer-9x](https://support.microsoft.com/hub/4338813/windows-help)

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
